Cyclops to Handler One.
They've reached the old high-speed
railroad terminal at point 122.
Sorry. They were jamming the radar,
and it took us a while to find them.
This is gonna be a rough fight
for the new kids.
What do we do?
Deploy our main force at 062,
then lure them in with another unit.
That would put them in range
of the remaining howitzers.
So we're fighting them
right in front of the base, huh?
If they make it through,
there's nothing but the minefields
and the howitzers
to keep them out, right?
But it's the best location we have,
if we're to survive.
Yes, my Queen!
Now for today's update on the war
from San Magnolia Military HQ!
Our nation's autonomous Juggernaut units
intercepted the Legion mechanized infantry drones,
December 2nd, Stellar Year 2148
dealt critical damage,
and forced them to withdraw.
Combat via highly advanced,
ethically responsible drones
has resulted in zero fatalities
on our side!
The day when our righteous nation finally smashes
the evil remnants of the wicked Empire is not far off!
Glory to the Republic of San Magnolia,
and to the five-color flag!
Hey, it's the Doll-Crushing Princess!
I heard you had another victory
against the Legion threat today,
stained with the blood of pigs!
That's why they call her Bloody Regina,
the bloody queen!
You learn to tell the difference
between men and pigs?
She never changes expression.
Who knows what she's thinking?
Getting demoted for the sake of those pigs...
Wearing a black uniform
when nobody else does...
The Legion won't even be around
in two years!
Her family's rich and famous, right?
Had she just done nothing,
she'd have life on easy street.
Morning.
There's something I want to check up
on from what you asked.
The additional settings
on the RAID Device.
Fine.
I'll be there in two hours.
Okay, see you then.
How many times do I have to tell you,
"Captain" Milizé?
Unauthorized use of the howitzers.
Unscheduled supply drops.
Taking direct command
of units not below you.
Do you know how many
complaints I'm getting?
Don't make me do extra work
for the sake of the damn Eighty-Six.
If you'd give me permission in advance,
you wouldn't have to tell me any of this,
Lieutenant Colonel.
What?
You, and all of them, are free
to complain all you like,
but it has nothing to do with me.
You little brat!
Know your place!
You're just a captain!
Are you sure you want me
to know my place?
Your subordinates' results reflect
on your own career.
What?
I'm currently the top Handler.
If my Legion kill rate goes down,
you risk not being promoted.
Right?
Watch your mouth, Captain.
Excuse me, Lieutenant Colonel.
I'll let you handle the supplies.
Okay.
Captain, I looked into
how many of the howitzers
in the rear of Southern Combat District 8
were still functional, and you were right.
It was around twenty percent.
I thought so.
Our total attrition rate
on the front lines—
Hey, look! Look! Snow!
Winter's really here, huh?
Cyclops to Handler One.
Do you read?
Yes. What is it?
We found an enemy unit
out on patrol.
We need your orders.
Understood.
Keep it up.
Cyclops, give me a report.
Sorry I'm late.
You're pretty early.
Get started with your chat.
Yeah.
Understood. Thank you for the report.
Yeah. I'll be waiting for those
Legion force estimates, Queen.
Yes, I'll do what I can.
Let's both work together
to do our best.
Of course.
You're our Handler.
We're counting on you.
You, too.
I need the info you give us
from the battlefield, Cyclops.
It's okay to call me
by my real name now, right?
If you aren't going to,
Shiden Iida
why did you ask?
Because that's...
my responsibility as a Handler.
You're always so serious
and formal, you know?
Think what you like.
Thanks to you, though,
we might live a long time.
I appreciate it, but we might be going
to Spearhead in a few months.
The strongest guy I know finally got sent
on Special Recon a while back.
He's probably dead now.
The headless Reaper who always used blades.
Which do you think will be first:
us going there or the Legion coming here?
I don't know.
But my job now is to prepare for the
large-scale Legion offensive I think is coming.
I've already decided to help you, but...
no preparations you make
will change a thing.
You're doing it anyway?
I'm doing it anyway.
But Cyclops, don't forget
your reports on patrol.
Roger!
They told me to survive, anyway.
They believed in me,
and told me to fight, and survive.
Teppy
To live up to the hopes of those
who are no longer with us...
Shin!
This is as far as I can go.
You can go the rest
of the way yourself, right?
You've got your comrades going with you.
You've really grown up, too.
Don't let me keep you a prisoner.
You can forget about me.
Oh, no.
I want you to remember me,
just once in a while.
Live free, be happy...
And once in a while, you know?
Just once in a while.
Be well.
And please be happy.
Brother!
I know.
I just want to chat a little.
You're awake, huh? Hello.
Will you tell me your name?
Oh!
Oh, the generals were all really worried,
so they made me wear this biohazard suit.
But it's rude to be wearing this, isn't it?
My name is Ernst.
And you?
Shin Nouzen.
Welcome to the Federacy of Giad!
"Giad"?
Oh, I should explain.
We defeated the Giad "Empire" that created the Legion,
and we changed it into a Federal Republic.
Well, because of that, we're still
fighting the remaining Legion, though.
We found you captured by the Legion
on the western front of the war.
Sorry, sorry.
Of course you're worried.
You were sleeping,
so we turned the windows opaque.
Neither you nor we entirely
understand what happened.
Later, when you remember,
if you could...
Sir! That's enough.
Sorry!
The scary lady's going to get mad at me,
so I'll be going.
But remember this.
You're the first foreign visitors we've had
since our nation's founding.
We were too busy with the Legion
to put together customs procedures.
But don't worry, we will not harm you.
I'm Ernst Zimerman,
provisional President of the Giad Federacy.
What does our analysis show?
It's safe to say they aren't agents
of San Magnolia or any other country.
And the odds that
they're a new type of Legion,
or perhaps a carrier
for a Legion bioweapon?
Our tests and the scan we did after they
were brought in show nothing irregular.
And the things they had with them?
It's a slightly older model,
but definitely a Dinosauria.
And the things on their ears?
A communication device, as they said.
It artificially recreates the mental links
that a certain family is capable of.
Revolutionary.
The safest thing for the Federacy
would be to eliminate them.
Shin,
you were out for three whole days.
Seriously, Kurena was bawling her eyes out.
I was not!
Shin, I know now's not a good time,
but be ready when you get better.
Sorry, we all feel the same way.
If you ever pull that shit again,
I will kick your ass.
I didn't mean to die—
You're going to make me mad.
Even if you didn't intend to die,
you knew you would if you fought alone.
We've all thought about it once, sure.
But that's why we can't forgive it!
Because we understand!
It's cheating.
Never do that again!
I was so worried!
Sorry.
But who knows what happens now...
So yeah, from now on,
you're citizens of the Federacy!
Huh?
We haven't seen you for a month,
and the first thing you say is "So yeah?"
Yeah?
You sure you want
to make a bunch of strange kids
who were kicked out
of their old country into citizens?
Wouldn't it be safer just to kill us?
Is that what you want?
What benefit do you get
from saving us?
A society which refuses to save children
because there's no "benefit"
is a society which in the end
benefits no one.
And if humanity can't survive except
by killing children because they're "strange,"
humanity would be better off dead.
Anyway, I'll be your guardian
for a while.
So rest a bit, see this country,
and then think about what you'll do.
Sankt Glykine Base
Those war machines we recovered
—the "Juggernauts"?
December 2nd, Stellar Year 2148
Their capabilities aside,
what was done with them is amazing.
I'd love to hear more.
Hey, I'm first.
We won't let you have them.
What?
High-mobility combat data and people
with actual combat experience against the data.
They're perfect as operators
for my prototypes.
They'd be wasted on those slow Vánagandr.
What did you say, spider woman?
What did you say, beetle?
You're all free to talk to them.
But I won't let them be operators.
We'd be no different from the Republic.
But they're all saying in
their counseling sessions
that they want to go back
to the battlefield.
That's because the battlefield
is all they know right now.
Actions should be met with rewards.
If they've fought for so long,
they should be given peace.
Especially if their homeland
refuses to do it.
I want the Federacy to be just, at least.
Because...
that is the ideal of mankind.
Let us save our pitiful comrades!
Let's save them!
The Eighty-Six are victims!
Victims!
Let us save our pitiful comrades!
They were all happy when you were saved,
Let's save them!
because they learned there was
a surviving country besides our own.
But when they learned
how you were treated,
they became overcome with the desire
to save you and your comrades.
This is my house,
but from now on it's your home.
Welcome!
Hurry!
Push that desk!
We need to hurry!
Welcome, poor souls who were banished
from your country!
Great Giad welcomes you
with pity and compassion!
We don't expect any kind of recompense
from low-borns like you,
so your thanks are enough!
Hey, red-eyes!
Why are you looking away?
I thought there might be someone else here.
You shut the door!
Are you making fun of me?
Yes.
This is the problem with low-born people
from the Republic.
Is this your daughter?
I hate to say it, but you need
to discipline her better.
Oh, no.
She's not my daughter.
Do you really think I'm the daughter
of this lowly bureaucrat?
I'm—
Frederica Rosenfort.
Some things happened,
and now she's staying here.
It's annoying to explain to everyone,
so I've got her down on
paper as my daughter.
But regardless,
you'll be living together for a while.
So I'd appreciate it if you'd think of her
as a slightly naïve little sister.
"Little sister," huh?
Oh, on paper, I've adopted you.
So you can call me "Dad,"
if you want.
I'm joking.
What's that on your neck?
Frederica, no.
I told you their situation.
You have wounds
you don't want touched, either.
I'm the cute little sister
you've been given to heal your wounds.
The family and home
and happiness you lost...
The noble and compassionate
Federacy is willing to give you.
Be very nice to me!
Big brothers and sisters!
Theresa, they're being mean!
Right, right.
Frederica, everything that just happened
was your own fault.
Was not! Was not!
I'm Theresa.
I'll be taking care of you.
Welcome home, everyone.
I'm bored.
They all went to sleep so early.
Sorry, I know you're tired.
I was holding on to this.
It was in your war machine.
Is it yours?
Yes.
Thank you, Theresa.
Not at all, sir.
Kids that age eat a lot.
It's fun to cook for them.
I'm sorry.
This is likely to be difficult.
Not at all.
Serving you is my job.
Do you think it's a stupid way
of trying to compensate for things?
That I'm using them
as a replacement?
No. They could never be that.
Every person is their own,
irreplaceable individual.
But still, people try to bury the past.
In whatever way they can.
Whom are you talking to,
Empress?
Kiri...
"It's Too Late."